<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrea Vanags&#39; SDS 348 Website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andrea Vanags&#39; SDS 348 Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>Andrea Vanags (av29824) Introduction: The two datasets I have chosen for this project contain information about suicides and earthquakes worldwide from 1985 to 2016. The suicides dataset contains qualitative (ex: sex, age, generation, countries) and quantitative data (ex: year, number of suicides, country population, gdp for year and per capita). The earthquakes dataset countains mostly quantitative values (ex:date, longitude, latitude, depth, magnitude), some qualitative (ex: ID, status, type) and quite a few N/As.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>project 2</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>0. Introduce your dataset and each of your variables in a paragraph. What are they measuring? How many observations? The &#39;HealthInsurance&#39; dataset including info from the the Medical Expenditure Panel Survey conducted in 1996 was recovered from the AER package. This dataset contains 8,802 observations on 11 variables, but the variables I will be focusing on are: age, gender, education, family, ethnicity, married, insurance, and health. The wrangled dataset was renamed as &#39;data2&#39; and it contains 1,258 rows (observations) for 8 columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reticulate: The Real Mind Meld </title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/10/test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/10/test-post/</guid>
      <description>On the wrong page? Maybe you&#39;re looking for my first project? Click below! Link to project 1
Still here?? Nice.
Let&#39;s look at how we can use R and Python together without wanting to tear your hair out in frustration: reticulate.
#R-code chunk library(reticulate) lookalike &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;who is dr. woodward&amp;#39;s celebrity look-alike?&amp;quot; #python code chunk one= &amp;quot;brian david gilbert&amp;quot; two= &amp;quot;and mathew gray gubler&amp;quot; #access R-defined objects with r. print(r.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description> One day I&#39;ll create a resume full of my un-marketable skills such as my ability to sing perfectly along to a swedish club song, or my amazing inability to touch my toes, but today is not that day. Instead, enjoy a listing of my marketable skills and academic achievements:
   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
